hello there this is the CBS code even
open source a podcast and the video
interview serious i'm your host cover
several times me is Thompson and we're
going to talk about the project called
chrome hi how are you hi I'm fine thank
you
sorry I'm fine thank you let's start
with introducing you a little bit there
please tell me a little about yourself
your background how did you get here ok
so i'm in thomaston i'm a software
engineer in the UK i went for a betting
and gaming company and have them for
about five years now and start tinkering
with computers when I was a kid and
eventually ended up spending some time
with a network engineer and then a
software engineer we know what PHP more
recently written a better go and mostly
i like to make tools and try and make
things to make other developers lives
easier basically and yeah not great deal
to say about me to be honest
oh ok uh how long have you been writing
open source stuff I'm think I really
soon
only start to get into it seriously for
the last couple of years or so and I
mean I'd I'd released bits of code I'd
written before that but they weren't
very useful and so only really in the
last couple years if I started started
thinking about what other people might
need and and try to make tools available
for them and I mean I think sharing code
is generally really good idea and I
think only recently have I thought
perhaps my code was useful enough but
people are actually using having that
experience is contributing to other
projects
yeah you so and i have been a maintainer
of the PHP client for the Easter
pathologic project for a while now and
it's not very active project but it's
used quite quite a few people and
altogether which project was
that you had light and a KGB client for
the API and so each analyte is a
collaborative text editor and I think
nowadays it is called the pad and really
know Jas and it's worth looking up
actually it's a good one to use a great
project and although other than that and
i made some small contributions here and
there made a fix to the window manager
that I use one called cat get out of my
way window manager written by a guy
called Sean Pringle and so really great
a lightweight tiling window manager i'll
rather floating window manager with the
great sport tiling just small bits here
and that usually just when I find
something has broken and i needed to
work i'll try and fix it
yeah that reminds me the the broken
window theory soon and fix your broken
window editor
okay whatever yeah yeah a but this
window manager slaton beauty is it so
hard to answer the the window managers
in c and I don't know c and but usually
I just my only real skill is just
figuring things out and just figure out
the things i need to achieve y1
basically so despite not knowing see
will help from google and couple of
tools that let me get a debug build and
figure out where the second thought was
happening I grow blog post blog post
about a while ago and entitled fixing a
segfault in bloom wwm and some Tom calm
and again I don't know see so it's
probably laughable to anyone who does
but it's more mostly an adventure in
finding a problem fixing it for me and
was accepted in the project
yeah yes I got my poll request managed
and I have no problem with it since it's
a really really stable project otherwise
that's great i mean that's a little bit
a little bit here a little there
and that's that's how it moves forward
racing yeah absolutely so so let's get
let's get to this project groan okay
what is it provided you build it so
professionally I deal with quite a few
HTTP API that return JSON and and some
of them are quite badly documented but
have very very large responses so
sometimes you know what you're looking
for in their response and and you can go
grab frighten some JSON and you find
that it's four five six levels d and so
you don't get any context to go with
that value can be really difficult to
and reason about the structure of that
JSON so and originally barrel think it's
34 years ago i wrote ground in PHP and
the idea was to take a JSON structure
and output hours a series of individual
assignments and was as valid JavaScript
so you would end up with something like
a song . i don't know city . name equals
leads for example and that means that if
you are grabbing for that value leads
you can see the whole path all the way
through and you just get that context
that allows you to see you know what
code do actually need to write to access
this value what things do i need to
traverse over and so mostly I wrote it
because I needed it and I didn't really
get any traction and initially I think
mostly because i'd written in PHP the
main feedback out for people was well
i'm writing know Jas or something like
that or even when i'm ryan c sharp or
pearl I I don't have PHP installed so I
can't use this thing it wasn't of used
to that many people
okay done yeah I noticed that recently
you switch it to recently underwent
actually uses you too
to go and you were written the whole
thing
yeah so I i did that earlier this year
and i've been writing and go on enough
for maybe two two-and-a-half years now
and and if i'm honest the main reason i
rewrote and go was that I was trying to
learn more go and something where I'd
already solved sort of some of the main
problems and I could just do it like a
straight port to go seems like a good
project to work on and but then I
realized that and this means that other
people can use this more easily so go
produces started Weiland binaries by
default which means i can build four
different operating systems and just
upload a binary to get help people can
just download it from it just works and
so I kind of took it from that start
adding more features and maybe a bit
more robust it more user-friendly and
and initially it was all just about
turning the JSON into these discrete
assignments which had some point became
a verb to grow so Jason gets ground and
it is the official way of putting it now
and I then decided that and for the tool
to be a really powerful and maybe a
little bit more than just exploration be
really great if you could do the other
going the other direction which is B
come on groaning or no gain some people
would have a lot and was a bit of debate
about early on then
but that means that you can alter the
structure of the data in its and in the
intermediate state when it's a list of
assignments with things like crap and
sad and walk if you like and then turn
the result back into JSON again and I
mean it's not the kind of thing you
should really be relying on scripts and
when you just need like a quick fix for
something hacking on a command line and
it turns out to be actually pretty
powerful trusting of
after I've tried to grope our time
trying to the opposite value and i like
that you basically take a JSON structure
which is that my problem is that in many
cases the JSON structure comes in SF 119
basically yeah not even there
I mean you could you can print up Jason
normally is a readable format even then
it's it's hard to grab for something
because you get the line but you don't
get the context but usually you just get
online and then you get the whole thing
and it's unusable
yeah for that purpose for reading so
what I really like this that you take
that format and and and show the whole
tree
although those other levels that go to
the point that there that i was looking
for the fact that it's it's actually
executable javascript I don't know where
is that is do do you feel it about you
I haven't and lastly it's about
predictability so and i mean when i
first read the tool i was trying to
think you know what format could i use
to output this data to make it
understandable and i thought i could
just write as though it was file paths
so like it slashes and I thought well
you know make the obvious thing to do is
to write in JavaScript so mean Jason's a
subset of of JavaScript and so I thought
maybe having my own subset as well would
make sense because then in theory at
least anyone who knows json would
immediately understand format and and
what different things mean so like what
the square braces mean for example
someone had already come up with that
formats for me I just needed to make it
work and I the fact that it is
executable transcript is almost more of
a curiosity in some ways but it means
that i could get away with not defining
the grammar properly initially and I
just sort of said the grammar is
anything that's valid JavaScript which
was
and maybe a bit too vague have now
started to define the grommet properly
and particularly when I've been dealing
with some bugs and things on the on the
one running phase and which is fun it is
it's a real experience me learning the
BBF that I think it's extended back a
snow form i think im so I I'm
self-educated so I didn't do computer
science or compiler theory or anything
so a lot of intensive googling to figure
it out and but yeah it's really think
there's an example in the readme you can
pipe the output into a doctor is file to
console that log at the end of it and it
it will output the object and and then
before the young running mode existed
I suppose that was kinda useful because
you could do the things we would grab
Duffy and remove certain statements or
you said to change the paths in things
and and then you could type into a
JavaScript file to get it back into JSON
and but it was always a bit flaky
because you need every step of the way
so your top level and statement has to
sort of say well as equals and the
object and then only then can you refer
to properties of the object whereas when
grounders is only one and process it can
imply all of that stuff from a single
statement and you don't need those
preceding statements just say I think to
sell if that makes sense
yeah yeah i think so i do thinking about
this latch thing that separating
installations like a fire pass right and
yeah that's not obvious solution that I
that came to my mind now but it's
obviously also broken because / can be a
value and then you have to escape it and
then yeah yeah so it's and and that and
I also that means i have to document it
up front you know what is this / mean
and coming up with my own syntax to
represent
arrays or objects and things like that
just just seems beyond the fact that you
even thought of it seemed silly in
hindsight and because there's already
something that works really well for
that
yeah yeah I think so yeah do you have
any plans for grow so busy a couple of
things I think needs some attention at
the the error handling is not very good
at the moment and so for example the
moment you'll get fairly cryptic errors
things like just our couldn't pass the
input statements which is pretty useless
particularly if you're putting you know
half a megabyte of of input into it got
you know somewhere in here is an error
ya know where I just just doesn't work
sorry and so I'm looking at package
errors which is a go package written by
de Chaney i think it is and which
provides could help you provide a bit
more context about the cause of errors
by sort of wrapping them because they go
up the call stack and but really I think
my lexer that is the ongoing needs some
attention in terms of actually giving
the user some context in terms of you
know what character was it that caused
the collector to choke and all you know
what exactly it was that was unexpected
so that people can figure out what the
problem is a bit more easily and so that
needs some work and there are a few bits
of code i think just need to be
factoring we're upset things globally
because it's easy and really it makes it
a bit difficult to test because I gotta
change global state on another test to
make things work and I'd like to change
how the adding colors to the grandma
airport works is kind of added in line
as the statements are built about the
mama
but then i need to do a sort to make
sure things are in the right order and a
natural or human source as well not the
sort of standard just less than greater
that and what not to do that I have to
strip the colors back out the statements
again and which is a bit of a pain to be
inefficient and I mean performance has
never really been a primary goal of the
tool but if it's unbearably slow then
people are going to use it
yeah and doesn't matter and I mean I i'm
a big fan of the the UNIX philosophy of
just do one thing and do it well is this
a bit of debate about what constitute
one thing so you know should grunting
and groaning be separate tools i don't
think so i consider them i think that's
what close enough to one thing that it's
okay and I'm not too keen on adding many
more features to it and the whole idea
was that the to let you use things you
already know like crap and said an ark
to get to get things done
so one of the common questions I get is
while washing agencies get here so JQ is
a tool for manipulating JSON and it is
an amazing tool it really really
powerful there's a lot more things and
then grown but it's only useful if you
already understand the structure of the
job of the JSON itself so if you know
the path to the key that you want and
there's not much in the way of discovery
that and it will do pretty printing and
things like that but again if you've got
half a mega JSON and you grab for
something and it's eight levels deep you
doing a lot scrolling to figure out
where that actually is and so really I
see it so that as a compliment to take
you and which yeah i think they can work
together i think probably not like in a
script or something like that but
certainly I find myself using ground to
figure out what the structure of the
JSON is and then i'll probably use
something like Jake you to do the actual
transformation
i'm feeling lazy now she's that ok uh
that's that's great i think we are
getting quite close to a time I've ever
yeah almost 20 minutes already so we're
talking about it while we were thinking
about that we will only have 10 minutes
or so
so it's interesting right is that
interesting hearing about it i do you
have anything uh the other thing that we
haven't talked about that you would like
to call I don't know tell people how to
do maybe maybe how to contribute or how
to get you so that count contributions
are always welcome and I mean if you
actually get excited when someone files
an issue
it means I've got some something to do
and then I was a little bit upset that I
kind of finished so speak and I didn't
have anything like to do on it and so
great just raising issues is the
simplest way to contribute and people
have got all requests or suggestions for
enhancements and things like that I'll
always consider them all and there's a
small contributing dock in the root of
the repository which suggests which is
just basically run the tests use go
format when the winters and and then
issue or request and i look at it and
yeah okay so i think that that's it
thank you for coming on the show and i
hope many people will start using crawl
anymore people people and you have more
ideas to help others
alright thank you ma'am thank you babe
you're talking too much weight